# Fisseha Berhane, Ph.D. Candidate Johns Hopkins University 443-970-2353 fisseha@jhu.edu

More than six years of data intensive research experience using R, Python, Matlab and GIS. Strong academic training and extensive experience with data mining and machine learning methods. Developed a rainfall prediction tool that uses various prediction models, including Random Forest, Artificial Neural Network, Support Vector Machines and Boosting, for any geographic location with Shiny, HTML, JavaScript, and CSS. Data Science enthusiast. In addition to the data science courses I have done in grad school, I have taken more than 20 edx, coursera and Udacity data science courses with R, Spark, Python, Matlab, and Hadoop and MapReduce. Have done various data science related projects. Please visit my website for details on the projects I have worked on, data science related courses I have taken in grad school, online data science certifications and more.

#### **Education**

### **Research Positions**

Graduate Research Assistant, Department of Earth and Planetary Science, Johns Hopkins University,
Baltimore, Maryland.

August 2011 – 2015

Graduate Research Assistant, Department of Natural Resources and the Environment, University of Connecticut, Storrs, CT 2009 – May 2011

# **Teaching Experience**

Teaching assistant (TA), Department of Earth and Planetary Science, The Johns Hopkins University,
Baltimore, Maryland. Spring 2013

Assistant Lecturer, Department of Civil Engineering, Mekelle University, Ethiopia 2006-2009

## **Publications**

Three peer-reviewed publications in the Journal of Climate (JCL), which is among the most prestigious Journals in Atmospheric Science, one in preparation and a master's thesis.

## **Presentations**

More than 12 presentations, including in prestigious international conferences such as the American Geophysical Union (AGU) and the American Meteorological Society (AMS).